[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
At the core of the decision tree algorithm is choosing the feature to split on and
ويتم في صميم خوارزمية شجرة القرار، اختيار الميزة المراد تقسيمها
that's the place we're going to modify it to also choose what to do with that
وكذلك المكان الذي سنقوم بتعديله، ونحدد ما سنقوم بفعله
missing data.
تجاه البيانات المفقودة.
Regarding the most important question in decision tree learning is
باعتبار أن السؤال الأكثر أهمية في تعلم شجرة القرار هو،
figuring out what feature to split up.
كيفية اكتشاف ما هي تلك الميزة التي سنقوم بتقسيمها.
And so now when we look at what features split on,
والآن، وبعد أن نعرف ما هي تلك الميزة التي سنقوم بتقسيمها،
we're not just going to decide what feature to split on,
فإننا لا نقوم بتحديد تلك الميزة التي نقوم بتقسيمها فقط،
we're also going to decide, which branch to take when we see a missing value?
بل نقوم أيضًا بتحديد الفرع الذي سنقوم من خلاله برؤية البيانات المفقودة.
And so conceptually, it's just a very very simplification
ومن الناحية النظرية، فإنها تعتبر خوارزمية بسيطة جدًا جدًا،
algorithm we described in the previous module.
والتي قمنا بوصفها في الوحدة السابقة.
But now, we're just going to add this extra search to figure out where to
ولكننا الآن، سنقوم بإضافة هذا البحث الإضافي لاكتشاف
put that missing data.
أين سنضع تلك البيانات المفقودة
Just like with grading learning decision trees,
وذلك فيما يشبه تدريج شجر قرار التعلم.
we can just focus on learning decision stump to understand what's going on here.
ويمكننا التركيز فقط على جذع قرار التعلم لمعرفة ماذا يحدث هنا.
So, we chose to split on credit.
ولهذا، اخترنا أن نقسم على الإقراض.
Credit can be excellent, fair or poor and the branch here on
ويمكن أن يكون الإقراض بوضع ممتاز أو مقبول أو ضعيف،
the right is the one where all data points have credit equals poor.
والفرع الموجود على جهة اليمين هنا، توجد به جميع النقاط التي يساوي الإقراض فيها وضعًا ضعيفًا.
And now, we might decide that the missing data is going to go into that branch.
ويمكن أن نقرر الآن، أن جميع البيانات المفقودة قد انتقلت لهذا الفرع.
So now we're going to take all the data that was missing and
ولهذا سنقوم الآن بأخذ جميع تلك البيانات التي كانت مفقودة،
the data where credit equals poor, and feed it into that node.
والبيانات التي يساوي الإقراض فيها صفرًا، ونقوم بتقديمها إلى تلك العقدة.
That's what's going to happen with categorical data.
وهذا ما سيحدث مع البيانات الفئوية.
Now when we have numeric data,
ولدينا الآن، بيانات عددية،
when they use those threshold splits that we discussed in the previous module.
وعندما نقوم باستخدام تلك التقسيمات وفقًا للحد الأدنى، والذي ناقشناه في الوحدة السابقة.
And in this case, when my threshold income is less than $50,000 or
وفي هذه الحالة، عندما يكون الدخل وفقًا للحد الأدنى، أقل من 50.000 دولار،
greater than $50,000.
أو يزيد عن 50.000 دولار.
And if we decided that missing data or data where the income is unknown,
وفي حال قررنا أنها بيانات مفقودة، أو بيانات مجهولة الدخل،
when the feed it to the same node of those the income was less than 50,000.
عندما نقوم بتقديمها إلى نفس العقدة والتي يكون الدخل فيها أقل من 50.000 دولار،
That's the decisions that we are going to try to make inside of our learning
فتلك هي القرارات التي سنحاول القيام بها،
algorithm.
داخل خوارزمية التعلم.
Now, we have to decide where this data's going to go.
الآن، علينا أن نقرر أين ستنتقل هذه البيانات.
So let's say, we choose to split a credit or considering splitting a credit.
ولهذا، دعونا نقل إننا اخترنا تقسيم الإقراض أو أخذنا تقسيم الإقراض بعين الاعتبار.
If we consider spilling of credit, what should we do with the missing data?
وفي حال أخذنا تقسيم الإقراض بعين الاعتبار، فما يجب علينا فعله مع البيانات المفقودة؟
Should we put it with people of excellent credit,
هل يجب علينا وضعها مع الأشخاص ذوي الإقراض في الوضع الممتاز،
for people with fair credit or with some people with poor credit?
أو الأشخاص ذوي الإقراض في الوضع المقبول، أو أولئك ذوي الإقراض في الوضع الضعيف؟
I don't know what's best or we have a principle for doing this.
أنا لا أدري أيها أفضل، أو أن لدينا أساسًا للقيام بذلك.
As the principle says, choose the branch that leads to the lowest classification
حيث إن الأساس يوضح، أنه يجب اختيار الفرع الذي يؤدي للنسبة الأقل للخطأ في التصنيف،
error, just like we did before.
كما قمنا بذلك سابقًا،
Let say, they were considering splitting on credit and we'll consider assigning
دعونا نقول، أننا أخذنا التقسيم على الإقراض بعين الاعتبار،
the missing data to the branch where the credit was excellent.
وأننا سنقوم الأخذ بعين الاعتبار أيضًا تعيين البيانات المفقودة إلى الفرع، حيث يكون الإقراض بوضع ممتاز
Let see what happens.
ودعونا نر ماذا يحدث.
So in this example, we have three data points
ولدينا في هذا المثال، ثلاث نقاط بيانات
with missing data, these three here.
بها بيانات مفقودة، تلك الثلاث هنا،
And we're considering assigning those data points to the branch where the credit was
وأننا سنضع بعين الاعتبار تعيين نقاط البيانات تلك إلى الفرع الذي يكون فيه الإقراض
excellent.
بوضع ممتاز.
So, we had two kinds of data.
ولهذا، فإنا لدينا نوعان من البيانات.
We had the observe data and then there,
وقمنا بملاحظة البيانات،
we had in the exon branch, we had nine safe loans, zero risk.
ومن ثم فقد أصبح لدينا في الفرع ذي وضع الإقراض الممتاز، 9 قروض آمنة و0 خطرة.
In the fair branch, we had eight safe loans and four risky.
ولدينا في الفرع ذي وضع الإقراض المقبول، 9 قروض آمنة و4 خطرة.
And in the poor branch, we have 4 safe loans and 12 risky.
الضعيف، 4 قروض آمنة و12 خطرة.
Now, we have the three extra data points.
والآن، فإن لدينا نقاط البيانات الثلاث الإضافية.
And in this three extra data points as you can see, there's two risky and one safe.
وفي نقاط البيانات الثلاث الإضافية تلك، فإنه يوجد كما ترى 2 قرض بوضع خطر و1 قرض آمن.
So, we're thinking about adding these two risky and
ولهذا، فإننا نفكر في إضافة نقطتي البيانات الآمنة تلك،
one safe into the excellent branch.
وكذلك نقطة البيانات الخطرة في الفرع ذي وضع الإقراض بالوضع الممتاز.
So, what are the grand totals here?
لذا، ما المجموع الكلي هنا؟
The grand totals are ten safe and two risky inside the excellent branch and
المجموع الكلي هنا، هو 10 قروض آمنة و2 خطرة، في داخل الفرع ذو الوضع الممتاز
then the same for the other two branches, because we're not in excellent data.
وأيضًا نقوم بذلك في الفرعين الآخرين؛ فلسنا بصدد بيانات في وضع متميز،
So what's the overall total error of the resulting decision tree?
ولذا، ما هو المجموع الكلي للخطأ في شجرة القرار الناتجة؟
Well, for the excellent branch, we're going to predict safe.
حسنًا، بالنسبة للفرع في الوضع الممتاز، سنقوم بالتنبؤ بالأمان،
So, we're going to make two mistakes.
ولذا، سنقوم بالتنبؤ بخطأين.
For the fair branch, we're going to predict safe.
بالنسبة للفرع في الوضع المقبول سنتنبأ بالأمان،
So we're going to make four mistakes and for the poor branch,
لذا سنقوم بأربعة أخطاء، وبالنسبة للفرع في الوضع الضعيف،
we're going to predict risky and we're going to make four mistakes.
سنقوم بالتنبؤ بوضع خطر، وسنقوم بأربعة أخطاء.
So overall, we're going to make 10 mistakes and our total was 40 data points,
ولذا، فإن في المجمل، سنقوم بعشر أخطاء، وسيكون مجمل عدد نقاط البيانات = 40،
so the total error here is 0.25 one-quarter.
ولهذا فإن الخطأ الكلي هنا يساوي 0.25 أي الربع.
Now we do the same for every single option, every single branch.
ولهذا، سنقوم بذلك أيضًا، لكل خيار وحيد، ولكل فرع وحيد.
So, we tried putting the unknown data with the excellent and got error 0.5.
ولهذا سنحاول وضع البيانات المجهولة مع الفرع بالوضع الممتاز، ونحصل على خطأ يساوي 0.5.
We tried to put it with the fair branch, we get A 0.25 error as well.
وحاولنا أن نضعه في الفرع ذي الوضع المقبول، وحصلنا على خطأ يساوي 0.25 أيضًا.
But if we try to put it with the last branch here,
ولكن إن حاولنا وضعه في الفرع الأخير هنا،
with the poor branch, we get an error of 0.225.
في الفرع ذي الوضع الضعيف، سنحصل على خطأ يساوي 0.225.
And so that's a lower error, so this is the winner.
وهذه نسبة الخطأ الأقل، لذا فهو الفائز.
So the best thing to do would be to assign
ولهذا، فإن أفضل شيء نقوم به يمكن أن يكون
unknowns to the poor batch to credit equals poor,
القيام بتعيين البيانات المجهولة إلى الفرع ذو الوضع الضعيف،
which is exactly what we did in the earlier tree.
وهذا بالضبط ما قمنا به في الشجرة السابقة.
This is the modification of the tree splitting algorithm to
وهذا تعديل لخوارزمية تقسيم الشجرة،
take into account missing data, gets a little complicated.
للأخذ في الاعتبار البيانات المفقودة، ويبدو الأمر معقدًا قليلاً،
But it's generally, kind of simple idea we just described.
ولكنه في العموم، نوع من فكرة سهلة والتي قمنا بوصفها.
You're leaving here for a reference, if you choose to implement it.
وأنت تغادر هنا للحصول على مرجع، إذا اخترت تطبيقه.
But overall, the fundamental concept is you can use this idea of embedding,
ولكن في المجمل، فإن المفهوم الأساسي هو، إنه يمكنك استخدام فكرة
handling of missing data inside of the learning algorithm to get better
الدمج والتعامل للبيانات المفقودة داخل خوارزمية التعلم
overall performance.
للحصول على أداء أفضل في المجمل.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]